You're going already?
（卓(たく)）もう行くのか？
予選 終われば見送れるのに
I could see you off after the preliminaries.
No way! You'd just cry, Dad.
（百合枝(ゆりえ)）
ダメ お父さん泣くでしょ？
それに予選 終わったら
きっとまた練習 練習だよ
Plus once they're over, I know you'll be all "Practice time!" again.
Your mom will miss you.
母さん さみしがるぞ
いつ帰ってくる？
When will you come home?
When I succeed.
成功したらね
お父さん 来てよ
Come visit me!
Overseas? Not me.
俺は外国なんぞ…
資金は どうしたんだ
Where'd you get the money?
（百合枝）車 売っちゃった
Sold my car!
Hey, now...
竜一(りゅういち)には ちゃんと言ったのか？
Did you tell Ryuuichi?
（百合枝）うーん 言ってない
No.
でも 竜(りゅう)ちゃんは大丈夫
But I'm sure Ryuu will be fine.
No one's waited for a hero longer than he has.
竜ちゃんくらい
ずっと昔から—
ヒーローを待ってる人は
いないから
いつかきっと
竜ちゃんの前にヒーローが現れる
So I know one will come for him someday.
Tell him to call Auntie Emiko if he wins.
優勝したら—
絶対 えみ子(こ)おばちゃんに
電話してって言ってね
（子供のペコ）
地球の平和を守るため—
I've come from the planet Ping Pong to protect Earth's peace.
ピンポン星から やってきた！
誰にも負けない
正義のヒーローなーのだあ！
An unbeatable hero of justice am I!
完全無敵のピンポンプレーヤーとは
俺のことでい！
Yes, I am the totally invincible ping pong player!
俺の名は…
My name is...
俺の名は！
（ドラゴン）いいのかね？ 膝
Is your knee okay?
This is...
これは…
ドラゴンと
遊ぶために—
I ran straight to the Don-Qui to buy it so I could play with you, Dragon!
即行 ドンキで
買ってきたんよ
That's a twiddle pen blade!
（観客）
反転式ペンだぜ　初めて見た
First time I've ever seen one.
He's gonna flip it while he plays?
（観客）回しながら打つの？
The inverted rubber was for when he got pushed back,
（道夫(みちお)）
下がった時のために貼った
裏ラバーだったが—
but Peco's biggest gift is his offensive, close to the table style of play.
ペコの一番の持ち味は
やっぱり速攻前陣だ！
それで 片面を
弾みのいい表ラバーに戻して—
So I gave him back one springy pips-out rubber,
and got a blade with a twiddle penhold grip to make twiddling easy.
自由に反転できる
反転ペンのグリップにした
これでフォアでもバックでも—
Now he can choose pips-out for speed or inverted rubber for spin for forehand and backhand!
弾みのいい表ラバーと
回転に強い裏ラバーを—
自由に使い分けることができる
Constant changeups should be hard to return, and drive the other guy crazy!
相手は 球質が
ころころ変わるんで—
うまく返せず
イライラするはずだ
簡単じゃないが ペコは
すぐにできるようになったよ
It's not easy, but Peco mastered it quickly.
（ドラゴン）
こんな おもちゃで—
Don't think you can match me with a toy like this.
私の相手が
できると思うな
My knee's messed up pretty bad, you know?
おいらの膝ね…
これが どうにも うまくねえんだな
けど あんた
高いとこいる選手だかんよ
But you're an athlete who's up real high.
うーんと
高いとこいる選手だかん
You're way up high, so I'm gonna climb on your back...
おいらも あんたの背中に
乗っけてもらって—
and fly.
飛ぶ
ふん お薬が必要な人のようだな
You sound like someone who needs medication.
人は空など飛べない
You're delusional. People can't fly.
飛べるはずもない
ハッ 人を病人扱いかい
Calling me sick in the head, eh?
Go!
（部員）よし いけ！
（部員）風間(かざま)！
You can do it, Kazama!
People can 't fly.
（ドラゴンの声）人は空など飛べぬ
If they could... If they could fly...
飛べるなら…
飛べるものなら…
A new age has dawned, and still I can't make a decision
My path is too straight for my taste, but I'll walk it
I can't choose just yet
I have to think about it
I have no idea what I want to do
I'm going crazy!
Comparing yourself to others just makes you depressed
I'm alone in this world
I'm always alone here
Still I'm gonna do it
Maybe there's nothing that only I can do
But there's no way that I
But there's no way that I won't try to leave my mark
I just want to have my fun, whatever the times
Hot damn, he 's intimidating.
（ペコの声）
すげえ圧迫感だな こりゃ
Guess that 's a world champ for you.
さすが
世界のてっぺん取った男だ
No—
いけねえ
のまれたら しまいだ
don 't let him get to you, or you 're done for.
Flinch and you 'll lose!
ビビりゃ負けるぜ
Fear him and you 'll die!
臆せば死ぬぜ！
よし
Okay.
いく！
Here I go!
A hero, huh?
（小泉(こいずみ)）ヒーローね
（ペコ）よし！
Yes!
やあ！
This guy...
（ペコの声）こいつ…
っしゃー！
Yeah!
Love-one!
（主審）ラブワン
Go!
（部員）サッ！ １本！
（部員）サッ！
Get him!
He brute-forced that backhand return.
He doesn't want to acknowledge Hoshino's talent.
I understand how he feels.
Mom...
母ちゃん
Amazing...
（アクマ）すげえ
Love-two!
（主審）ラブツー
Whoa, he went from there all the way to the fore side.
（毛利）速(はえ)え…
んだば あの位置がら
フォアまで回り込んだ
He's provoking him.
（猫田(ねこた)）挑発してんねや
（ドラゴン）っしゃー！
Yeah!
っしゃー！
クソ！
Damn!
（小泉）ちょっといいかね？
Got a moment?
What is it?
（スマイル）何です？
Hoshino's playing.
（小泉）星野(ほしの)の試合 やってるよ
応援せんのかね？
You're not going to cheer him on?
先生はヒーロー信じます？
Do you believe in heroes?
（小泉）ヒーロー？
Heroes?
He always appears when I'm in a pinch.
ピンチの時に必ず現れて—
No matter how trapped I am,
僕が どれだけ深くに
閉じ込められてても—
he always comes to save me.
助けに来てくれるヒーローです
Do you believe in these "heroes," Mr. Tsukimoto?
（小泉）
君は信じるのか？ ミスター月本(つきもと)
そのヒーローとかいうのを
Yes. I've been waiting for him for a long time now.
（スマイル）はい
もうずっと長いこと—
彼が来るのを
待っています
そして今日 彼は帰ってくる
And today he's coming back.
"He"? Who?
（小泉）彼？ Who？
Enter the hero! Enter the hero! Enter the hero!
（子供のペコ）
ヒーロー見参 ヒーロー見参
ヒーロー見参！
You're a cool guy.
（ペコの声）
あんた かっちょいいよ
俺 そういうの好きさ
I like that.
But don't think you can stay up there and look down on everyone forever.
でもね—
いつまでも そうして—
人 見下すとこ
登ってられっと思うなよ
（スマイル）彼が帰ってくる
He's coming home.
I 'm the hero!
（ペコの声）ヒーローは
俺だぜ
Me, got it?
俺だかんね！
My name is...
俺の名は…
俺の名は！
星野 裕(ゆたか)だ！
Hoshino Yutaka!
And don't you forget it!
そこんとこ—
よろしく！
You 'll learn one day.
（ドラゴンの声）
いずれ お前も知るだろう
The anguish of invincibility.
常勝の憂い　称賛の苦痛
The pain of praise.
The pressure of burdens.
背負うものの重圧
The isolation and anguish.
孤立と苦悩
Eventually your effort will feel meaningless, and victory will feel hollow.
やがて お前は
努力を無意味に—
勝利を むなしく感じるだろう
（風間理事長）だが お前は決して
その疑問に立ち止まってはならない
But you must never let those doubts stop you.
（道夫）いけねえぜ ペコ
Not good, Peco!
That leaves you vulnerable.
（風間理事長）それは隙を生む
Nine-love!
（主審）ナインラブ
Vulnerability brings defeat.
（風間理事長）隙は敗北を呼ぶ
Defeat is death.
敗北は死
（道夫）風間の流れに乗るな
Don't let Kazama set the pace!
You have to thirst for victory with all you 've got!
（ドラゴンの声）
強く ただ強く勝利を望め
（道夫）裏面 使え　裏だ ペコ
Use the reverse side, Peco.
Ten-love!
（主審）テンラブ
The reverse...
（道夫）裏…
（ペコ）くっ
Yes!
（道夫）よし！
Thirst!
（ドラゴンの声）強く
With all you 've got!
ただ強く！
（主審）イレブンラブ
ゲーム トゥ 風間選手
Eleven-love!
Game goes to Kazama!
Hey, kid!
おい 小僧！
Don't you dare think half-assed tactics will work on me!
付け焼き刃の戦型
私に通じるなどと決して思うな！
It disgusts me!
不快だ！
チクショウ
かっちブーだな ドラゴン てめえ
Damn it.
You're a cool guy, Dragon.
愛してるぜ
I love ya.
Drive.
（ドラゴンの声）ドライブ
Short pips backhand.
バック表
読まれてる
変え方が杓子(しゃくし)定規だ
Peco's being predicted.
His changes are too by the book!
You know better, Peco.
（オババ）
違うだろ ペコ
（ペコ）あっ
（ドラゴン）っしゃー！
Yeah!
（ドラゴンの声）
勝利への近道はない
There is no shortcut to victory.
You must climb that steep mountain one step at a time.
険しい山を一歩一歩 登るのだ
There 's an abyss down below, and it never ends.
下には深淵(しんえん)が広がり
終わりはない
Your only choice is to keep climbing!
登り続けるしかないのだ
（子供のドラゴン）父さん！
Dad!
（のりお）鳥はいいなあ
Birds sure have it good.
この山より
ずっと高いとこまで すいすいだ
It's so easy for them to get all this way up!
飛行機のない時代から—
You figure they've watched our ugly wars and stuff since before there were airplanes?
下界の醜い戦なんかを
眺めていたのかな
鳥に生まれたかったなあ
I wish I'd been born a bird.
Dad, watch out.
（子供のドラゴン）
危ない 父さん
Dad!
父さん！
Don't cry in front of people.
（風間理事長）人前で泣くな
敗北は死を意味すると思え
Understand that defeat means death.
Compromising is like cutting off your own arm.
妥協は
腕を切り落とすに等しい
勝利の中にのみ真実がある
In victory is where we find truth.
Win, Ryuuichi.
勝て 竜一
For your family.
家族のため 海王(かいおう)のため—
For Kaiou.
ポセイドンのため　勝て！
For Poseidon.
Win!
I want carpaccio.
（子供）
カルパッチョ食べたい
Oh, that should be just right!
（親）
あら 手ごろそうね
I wanna eat udon! Udon!
（子供のドラゴン）
俺 うどん食いたい
うどん うどん！
Oh, but...
（親）あら でも…
Udon! Udon!
（子供のドラゴン）
うどん うどん
絶対うどん！
It's gotta be udon!
Well, that's that.
（親）
しょうがないわね
竜ちゃん
一度 言いだしたら—
Once Ryuu's made up his mind, he won't listen.
聞かないから
Let's do udon then, honey.
（親）
じゃあ おうどんにしましょう
What?
He wasn't popular. That's why there are so few wreaths!
（風間理事長）
人望がないから花輪も少ない
Ryuuichi, order five more.
竜一 ５基 注文しろ
And Emiko, sick now, of all times?!
えみ子さんも こんな時に…
Your husband was doing weird business. That's why you get weird diseases!
旦那が下手な商売してるから
変な病気になる
I'm fine.
（えみ子）お母さんは平気
親類には親類のルールがあるから
Families have their own rules.
Don't think anybody will save you, because nobody will!
（風間理事長）
誰かが助けてくれると思うな
誰も助けてくれない
If you don't want to be bullied, get stronger.
いじめられたくなかったら
強くなれ
勝って勝って 勝ち上がれ！
Win and win and rise to the top!
What's wrong, hero?!
（ドラゴン）どうした ヒーロー
Well?!
どうしたよ！
You're the hero, aren't you?!
ヒーローなのだろうが！
おいおい 風間君　ちょっと…
Hey, Kazama, calm down...
Aren't you going to fly?
飛ぶのだろうが
Aren't you going to save everyone?
皆を救うのだろうが
Yup.
（真田(さなだ)）えらい気迫ばい 風間
Kazama's really worked up.
He never gets like that, even in the Interhigh finals.
本戦の決勝でん あげんはならん
Yeah.
（猫田）せやな
どうやらペコのやつ—
Looks like Peco's brought His Majesty's wrath down on him.
御大の逆鱗(げきりん)に
触れちまったようだね
自分の勝利は
宿命でなければならないと—
Ryuuichi believes his victory must be fated.
竜一は信じている
それが必然でなければ
ならないと
That it has to be an inevitability.
多分 やつにとって
卓球は—
I imagine table tennis brings him only pain.
苦痛なだけなのだろう
That is one kind of strength.
そういう強さもある
だが…
But...
（主審）イレブンワン
ゲーム トゥ 風間選手
Eleven-one!
Game goes to Kazama!
I'm gonna go.
ほいじゃ
行ってくんよ おいら
Hoshino.
（大田(おおた)）星野
（ペコ）うん？
Huh?
何つうか その… あれだ
Well, uh...
Well, you know... Go get him.
（大田）頑張れ
（ペコ）ういっす
On it.
He's shriveled completely.
（小泉）
完全に畏縮してるな あれは
（大田）あっ
（小泉）膝も—
His knee's not working with him, either.
折り合いがついていないか
（ドラゴン）痛むかね？ 膝が
Does your knee hurt?
（ペコ）
ヘヘ 優しいね 竜ちゃん
You're so nice, Ryuu.
ほいじゃ お願い
So, will you let me win our next game?
次のゲーム おいらにくりっ
Absurd.
笑止
Then don't ask.
なら聞くな
（ペコの声）
ロング？ ショート？
Long? Short?
Don't think, Peco; you don't have the brains for it.
足りねえ頭
使うなよ ペコ
It 's long! I 'll return it down the middle!
（ペコの声）
ロング？ ならミドル
But he loves that!
しかし得意
ねえのか 弱点
Doesn 't he have any weaknesses?
My stamina won 't last if he
keeps hitting all over the place.
こんなに散らされたら
スタミナもたねえ
You know better, Peco.
違うだろ ペコ
（ペコの声）ペース配分が…
I can 't pace myself...
That's not your game.
（オババ）そうじゃねえだろ
Yeah!
（ドラゴン）っしゃー！
（ペコの声）はぁ… 強(つえ)えわ
He 's good.
これでは
ファーストのリプレーだぜ
It 's turning into a replay of our first game.
I can 't attack fast since he keeps pulling me away from the table.
台から引き剥がされちまって
速攻できねえ
What do I do? Oh man...
どうしよう　トホホ…
What 's that weird song?
（ペコの声）何？ 変な歌
（スマイルの声）相手は強い？
Is he a tough opponent?
（ペコの声）卓球の権化さ
He 's the embodiment of table tennis.
You can find the fun in it, Peco.
（スマイルの声）
ペコなら楽しめるよ
遊んでると
あっという間に時間が過ぎる
Time flies when you 're having fun.
卓球してる時—
Whenever you played, you had such
a good time you 'd forget any injury.
ペコは
どんなケガも忘れて遊んでた
Your knee is fine.
膝だって大丈夫
You always said the stronger your opponent,
ペコ いつも言ってた
遊ぶ相手が強いほど
高く飛べるって
the higher you could fly.
Yeah.
（スマイルの声）飛べる？
Can you fly?
Yeah!
Yeah.
What is that?
（子供のペコ）何？ それ
（子供のスマイル）変？
Is it weird?
（子供のペコ）うん ちょっとな
Yeah, a little.
ヒーローの歌 僕が作ったんだ
It's the hero's song. I wrote it.
（ペコ）
エッヘヘヘへヘ エヘヘヘヘヘ
That's scary... What's with him?
Don't ask me.
Hey, Dragon!
（ペコ）おい ドラゴン
I'm gonna teach ya something!
おめえに教えてやんよ！
Table tennis is a freaking blast!
卓球っつうのはな—
めたくそ楽しいんだぜ！
I can fly!
（ペコの声）おいら飛べる
ピカピカ見える！ ピンピン動く！
I shine like a star!
I move like lightning!
Racing impulses!
インパルス走る　永久記憶不滅！
My memory lives forever!
I 'll blow you away, Dragon!
飛ばすぜ ドラゴン
My reactions, my reflexes... They 're faster
than the speed of sound—the speed of light!
反応！ 反射… 音速！ 光速！
いい子だ
Good boy.
それでいい
That's the way.
I move like lightning!
（ペコの声）ピンピン動く！
But I need more speed.
もっと もっと 速く 速く！
Faster! Faster!
Hey!
（卓）おい！ 裏！
Reverse!
Now I see.
なるほどね ヒーローか
He's a hero.
Look at me, Smile.
（ペコの声）見てくれ スマイル
おいら こんなにピンピン動く
Look how fast I move!
だあ！
でやぁ！
（主審）イレブンシックス
Eleven-six!
Game goes to Hoshino!
ゲーム トゥ 星野選手
You're the Hero, Aren't You?!
Pips-in: a drive.
（ドラゴンの声）裏ドライブ
バック表！
Backhand reverse!
That's it.
そうだ
（ドラゴンの声）表か？
Pips-out?
そう
Good!
（歓声）
（主審）ファイブオール！
Five-five!
Yeah!
っしゃー！
（ドラゴン）ちっ
（ペコ）イエーイ！
Yeah! This is a game!
遊びだよ 遊び
Either rubber's fine!
ラバーなんか
どっちでもいいかんよ
What a surprise.
He's got good instincts.
This must be hard for Kazama.
Maybe not.
Hoshino's style is offbeat.
It's like he loves the sport so much he can't hold it in.
Playing someone like that...
For me at least, it's...
（ペコ）っしゃー！
Yeah!
あんにゃろう
That little brat!
When'd he learn to chop?
カットなんて
いつ覚えやがったんだ
Kazama panicked and hit it hard.
風間は焦って 強打したね
（ドラゴンの声）ヒーローなど…
There are no heroes!
You can only rely on your own strength!
頼れるのは己の力のみ
What amazing reflexes.
（アクマの声）すげえ反応だ
Eleven-eight!
（主審）イレブンエイト
ゲーム トゥ 星野選手
Game goes to Hoshino!
Oh yeah!
っしゃー！
They're tied.
Yeah.
Kazama!
（真田）風間！
膝なら心配ねえかんな
Don't worry about my knee.
２人して思い出の試合にするべ
Let's make this a match to remember.
愛してるぜ ドラゴン
I love ya, Dragon.
チュッ
Smooch.
フッ 図に乗るな
Don't push your luck.
（ドラゴン）ふん！
やあ！
シャラッ！
Yeah!
（ペコ）うっ
（主審）アウト！
Out!
Yes!
（ドラゴン）シャラッ！
（卓）よっしゃー！
Yeah!
Five-six, Kazama!
（主審）
ファイブシックス　風間選手
This is a good game.
（のりお）ほら 竜一
Here, Ryuuichi.
That's great.
うまいな　上手だぞ 竜一
You're good at this, Ryuuichi.
Is it fun?
楽しいか？
Are you enjoying this, Ryuuichi?
面白いか？ 竜一
Forward! Forward!
（海王の部員たち）前！ 前！
（ペコ）えい！
Don't back down, Kazama!
（部員）
下がるな 風間！ 前！ 前！
Forward! Forward!
Shut up, you morons!
（ドラゴン）うるさい！ バカ！
Yeah!
シャーッ
He was smiling.
（真田）笑(わろ)うとったぞ
Why?
（猫田）なんでや？
Ryuuichi...
竜一
All my cells are singing with joy.
（ドラゴンの声）
全身の細胞は狂喜している
They 're ordering me to move faster...
加速せよと命じている
"Faster! Faster! "
加速せよ 加速せよ
集中力が外界を遮断する
My focus blocks out the outside world.
We 're moving so fast it feels
like the world is at a standstill.
膨張する速度は静止に近い
He matures at breakneck speed as if it 's normal.
やつは 当然のように
急速な成長を遂げる
瞬発する肉体
His body explodes into motion.
He is gradually pulling ahead.
次第に引き離されてゆく
I feel I am gradually being left behind.
徐々に置いてゆかれる感覚
It 's clear who the better player is.
優劣は明確
But I don 't feel anxious.
しかし焦りはない
全力で打球している
I 'm hitting with all I 've got.
I 'm reacting with all I 've got.
全力で反応している
おびえる暇などない
I don 't have time to be afraid.
Is something wrong?
（ペコ）どうかしたんか？
いや
No.
I'm feeling great, really.
いい気分だ
実に
Heh, me too.
ヘヘッ そうな
Yeah.
It's match point for me, Dragon.
おいら マッチポイントだぜ
ドラゴン
Yeah...
（ドラゴンの声）ああ
私はここまでだ ヒーロー
This is as far as I go, hero.
Oh my.
（ペコの声）あらら
（ドラゴンの声）
私の羽では限界だ
My wings can't take any more.
また連れてきてくれるか？
Will you bring me here again?
そうか
I see.
ニヒ
（ドラゴンの声）
全身の細胞は狂喜している
All my cells are singing with joy.
加速せよと命じている
They 're ordering me to move faster...
加速せよ 加速せよ
"Faster! Faster! "
The hero matures at breakneck speed.
ヒーローは急速な成長を遂げる
He is gradually pulling ahead.
次第に引き離されてゆく
I feel no anxiety.
焦りはない
おびえる必要などない
There is no need to be afraid.
There is no need to be afraid!
おびえる必要などないのだ
I like this place.
ここはいい
It 's glorious.
ここは 素晴らしい
You were so cool, Dragon.
（ペコの声）
カッコよかったぜ ドラゴン
That 's right...
（ドラゴンの声）そうさ
We can fly.
飛べるのだ
People can fly.
人は飛べるのだ
A red sun stares at me
The world goes blurry when I yawn
My wishes fluctuate like a metronome
Everything tells me this is the end
I do have some dreams, you know
Sometimes we breathe
and just seem to inhale the smoke of someone
somewhere out of sight
Then we are pure determination
I don't understand this wonderland
I won't get wet even if it rains
This is a wonderland
Once I've made it through this long tunnel
I'm sure that someone will kiss me